99 of time you will not be having a
single one-stop solution for a problem
okay because problems are very complex
let me tell you that
you would be having okay at times you
will have solution
then we'll take data we'll see and then
we'll come up with a long-term solution
[Music]
hello everyone welcome to yet another
podcast for this podcast we have with us
mr
so before starting the podcast i would
like to give a brief introduction about
sir
sir he's done his bachelor's from triple
iit bhuttneshward he has done his mba
from example nation
and now he's currently working as a
senior product manager at icici
so welcome to this podcast and
we would like to start this podcast by
you giving a brief introduction about
your role at icici bank what are your
dated responsibilities what are your
kpis what are your key areas what does
the company expect from you as a senior
product manager
okay first of all thank you for
inviting me here it's always a pleasure
to share and discuss about
things and
topics and ideas
so currently i'm working uh as you said
i'm working with isa bank as a senior
product manager
so specifically i work with the
department of mobile banking
if you must be aware of the mobile app
that is i mobile pay of isa bank i'm in
that team i'm handling i'm in the team
that handles this app
uh
okay so first uh
a bit of generic knowledge about product
management
now if i see
in corporate there are two types of
profiles one is a generalist profile one
is
what a
specific profile or a specialist profile
okay
when you talk about development
developers coders are
data scientists data analysts
so they require a very specific kind of
skill
to be able to you know
perform their activities to be able to
uh key in their deliverables
they are called specialists
or you can say our
the people who do ms and then they go
back to work in uh you know
pharmaceutical companies they're very
specialist kind of roles okay
where you need to uh
have certain amount of skills certain
type of skills uh which the company can
use
but whereas there are there is another
kind of profile that is a generalist
profile
product management comes in that what it
means is you don't have to be specialist
in every domain but you need to have a
basic know-how or a functional knowledge
about all the domains right
so basically product management
is a type of generalist profile
where
you need to
know something on technology you need to
know something on
marketing you need to know something on
you know the latest design language if
i'm talking about you know digital
product manager because right now most
of the profiles are digital every
company is trying to be digital it's
like a great space to be right right now
so when you are talking about digital
means it's either a web app or a mobile
app
let's say mobile app mobility is taking
over the entire world right now
uh
so when it comes to mobility you need to
know something about designs you may not
be knowing all the technical support
designs but you should know what a
journey looks like what what circums
what what's ux what's ui
okay and apart from that
the main thing is creativity you need to
have some kind of creativity because you
need to put everything together in the
plate that's the job of a product
manager
the tech team will do their job the
research team will do their job the
sales team will do their job the
uh designers will do their job you need
to put everything all the morsels of
different department and interpolate
them together so you need to have that
managerial skills so
i get a lot of questions uh from the
budding mba uh experience that what it
takes to be a product manager
so the answer is not you know it's not
that character you take these subjects
and you will get selected as a support
manager it's not like that but yeah what
i can tell is be
perspective perceptive to everything all
the subjects know something about all
the subjects know at least the
importance some key things about all the
you know domains that will actually help
you but yes currently i what i would say
you need to be tech savvy a bit of tech
savvy i'm not saying you need to know
all the coding and development
things but you need to be a bit
tech-savvy what's going on in this world
what's going on in the tech industry
because most of them are
they have implications in all the
see at the end of the day what is
product management you need to create a
digital product out of thin air right
so it takes a lot of things it takes a
lot of stakeholders so product
management is more about stakeholder
management
yeah
and
good documentation skills
good follow-up skills
yeah
and
good listening skills at times you need
to listen to your end customer we we
make it a point that when suppose a
customer raises an issue we need to call
our customer and we need to understand
what's the problem and are we really
solving the right
problem or are we just you know hovering
around
so these are all the skills that support
managers you need to have
this is all about you know when i say uh
space so this is what i do as well in my
um
in the bank in my team uh
we uh take customer feedback we take our
different stakeholders feedback and we
try to improve our product
some modules we try to revamp them we
try to
uh you know kind of redesign them if
required redevelop them if required
so i
so specifically in icc bank i am
handling the new projects department
uh wherein
we have a running app we need to
revamp some of the modules of the app
that is what i'm handling right
so when you when you say
means
it's like
bringing in new or technologies into the
app or it's like if there is some
technical problem with the customer is
not liking something changing that so
what is exactly a revamp
so there are two types of remap
one is just a design remap the front end
as you as you look
in to inside the app or you are looking
onto the app okay you
see the change in the ui
okay the screen front end screen but the
back end is all the same
they all link to the same table the same
database the development is same the
develop i mean the coding is same in the
back end that is one kind of revamp
that's called a design revamp or a
redesign exercise okay
revamp if i say then it will be a more
of a redesign recoding
retesting everything is different the
reason why we go for these kind of
things is usually
see when an app is old like i'll give
you the example of the imobile pr this
app started in 2008
when the entire in the entire nation
nobody knew about mobility applications
we started this app
on this indian
base okay
so uh
then in 2000 2008 if our app is getting
started you need to you know update the
app regularly so that it you know kind
of
is relevant in the current
market right so in 2015 we took a
revamping exercise
wherein the entire design was changed
the entire back end development was
changed yeah
so
that that was in 2015.
since then our app is still running on
that database
okay so now we need to also revamp
that it's high time right now because we
have all we have we're already in the
you know
in that space where technology is kind
of uh you know
factoring in in our lives to a large
extent to our corporate life also so
that's what that's the reason i think
and currently i think our
country is also in that phase wherein
technology is going to be a trendsetter
so that's the reason why we thought we
are revamping it again revamping in the
sense we are redesigning we are recoding
it
we are going to the entire exercise
again
so that's the part of the code manager
so in product management when you were
giving this answer you raised
two very uh important points one is as a
product manager you need to know the
basics of everything
like what's going behind reporting you
need to know that what's happening in
the financial part what's happening in
the marketing part just the basics of
everything need to be clear so that is
very important because
sometimes i feel when uh
i interview someone who is a product
manager say even in a more technical
company than icsa bank like in a
microsoft people feel like oh you need
to have a lot of coding knowledge as
well in order to be a product manager
but that is a myth you just need to know
the basics you don't need to know what
exactly the food the developer is
putting in or the cs guy is putting it
you need to know okay this is the
process he is using this is the code you
will put and this is how you will do
you you need to know
or you need to ensure that the code that
has been put
it has
passed all the positive scenarios all
the negative scenarios or all the error
handling mechanisms
right we in our term in our language and
mobile product management we have
something called zero state zero state
positive state and negative state
so a positive state is a happy flow
i mean a customer comes pays the bill
goes away on the app that's a happy flow
it's a very
you know unidirectional flow it's a very
happy
uh a zero state is if if it's a first
time customer
when i come to the app i do not i have
never used that app i do not have any
pending bills to pay i it's a blank
screen on my app
okay so that's a zero state that's a
first time customer
so how is the experience going to be for
that first time customer
that is something we have to get as a
product manager and we have to con you
know
change that or transform that into
technical requirement to the developers
yeah i think these customers will also
be very important for you so that they
again come back on the app and use it if
their first time experience is good
of course because we would rely on
customer stickiness and
so far as stickiness is concerned yeah
first-time customers to repeat customers
is very important for you for us
yeah so
so these kind of things you know you
have to con you have to convert these
kind of you know experiences into
requirements
and then pass it on
groom the developers so that they also
understand what we are trying to do
because if they don't then not going to
code it
and of course we will not be able to
know if that quoted it or not because
some people may have some understanding
about the development some java some
python but it's very because see mobile
banking codes are very complex very
complex it's very difficult to figure
out what it is for even the developers
struggle at times so
so it's so that's what i'm saying so
basically yeah you need to have some
kind of tech uh understanding some kind
of language development language
understanding to sail you through
smoothly
another another question that comes up
is uh the differentiation between a
technical program managed a product
manager and a business product manager
so if you can elaborate on that
difference as well because a lot of
people ask this question that what is
the difference between a technical
product and a business product manager
so basically i see there are a couple of
factors that determine if you are a
technical product manager or you are a
business product manager okay
uh
like in banks in icsa bank we have two
departments one is
the depart so basically department of
mobile banking is a department it has
two subdivisions one is the business
side one is the tech side
okay both of them are from icc man
so the business uh department
uh product managers there they handle
the
uh design aspect they handle the journey
aspect okay of the app
what new features are supposed to be put
what
what are the latest trends in the
in the mobile banking industry
how can we benchmark
our app to
other international
good
banking apps there are so many good
banking apps in
the international market in u.s
australia and in europe so
those kind of things
getting
the insights from the market from our
research we have a research team as well
from our designers what is the what is
apple uh design lab doing uh these days
what are the latest you know uh design
components that they have launched they
do that they do that very systematically
what is the
there is something called material
designing lab from google
they also come up with design guidelines
what are they doing okay you see at the
end of the day again you don't have to
design it okay but you need to know what
are those guidelines so that you can
actually discuss with your designer that
this is what we want this is what we
won't want this is the clear direction
that we want to give let's see means you
need to ask for a basic understanding of
the coding understanding they will have
but the technology understanding that
this is trending this is coming in the
market or this is the technology so how
do we implement in it in our app or how
do we implement it at icici bank so you
need to have that knowledge and then the
implementation part may be the borders
they can take that responsibility but to
come up with the idea to come up with
the knowledge is also part of the yes so
so so this i told about the business
product manager let's uh talk about the
tech product management now what the
tech product manager will do uh the
business product manager is going to
tell this is what i want to add this is
what i am visioning for this app this is
these are the modules that i have
envisioned
now
now they will like we will give a
business requirement document to the
tech folder
okay what they will do is they will see
how this which environment can support
these kind of requirements
what are the design language sorry what
are the coding language we are going to
use what is the server that we are going
to use
which which all vendors we have to open
to give different kind of
deliverables to us
you know because there are so many
specialists in the industry a one vendor
can do analytics better than someone one
vendor can do this better than someone
so he that
the the guy's responsibility is to have
the right fit for the business
requirement
from tech side again that guy also does
not
okay that guy mostly does not put but
yeah he has a deeper understanding about
the servers about uh yeah you know all
those the databases you know how um
the apis are different types of apis
this is the they have a more finer
understanding okay uh similarly so
basically you know it's it's basically a
team
yeah it depends on your skills which
profile you join i have many friends who
are technical approach managers they're
all support managers yeah but they can
they handle the tech side so as for your
deliverables
it is uh concluded that you are a
business program manager or a tech
product manager in some startups you may
be doing
both you may be doing both
yeah so again i have uh another doubt uh
which people have in which even i had
before i did these podcasts is a
difference between i see a number of
companies giving as program managers and
the number of giving giving as product
managers is it just the difference of
name of their roles and responsibilities
are kind of same or is there some sort
of difference in the roles and
responsibilities i've spent in a product
and a program manager
see right now i am seeing a lot of uh
you know this program manager name
coming up during my time it's it was not
that i mean before five years we
backtrack
this term was very uh rarely used but
what i understand technically i mean let
me first tell you technically
see
a product means it's a combination of
modules
okay different modules or different
programs okay
now
you are a product manager okay when
i'll give example of the imobile pair we
have more than 250 modules in the in one
single app if the customer doesn't know
that obviously because it's a small
screen right so
can you explain when you say module what
do you exactly mean because module means
let's say
i'm also very much
very technically happy so if you can
explain
the problem so so i'll tell you uh you
so basically uh upi payments you know
right bill payments you know right fun
transfer you know right so let's say
these are one-on-one modules okay before
selecting similar features like uh
different features yeah yeah for the end
customer these are different features
so uh
we have more than 250 features okay but
obviously we it's very difficult to you
know showcase them in the app very
difficult to um you know
get the accessibility of those features
okay so what we have is for important
features we consider them as programs
okay okay
and each and there is a person or a team
small team that manages that entire
program for example the upi the upi
feature or the program or the module in
the app is being managed by a separate
team not separately it's our team only
separate set of people with again set of
skills
yeah
they would be knowing everything about
upi they would be knowing what it takes
to
create an end-to-end journey about the
upa they'll be managing the live issues
coming from the customers regarding upi
so that that's a program
so in this technically in this case i
can say that this particular person is a
program manager
okay this is how i can this is called
again technically in some companies the
program is in itself so big that in
itself it's it's a product
so that that is where maybe uh this you
know bifurcation of program manager and
product manager has come
right but
a product a program manager at times may
be a product manager as well
right
there are some companies where
let's say about you know which are not
proved companies
they do some kind of
services
maybe
a marketing consulting company okay
marketing consultancy uh
okay
so for them program manager makes more
sense
yeah because they don't have products uh
even uh when i interviewed someone from
amazon there also they say program
manager after that product managers
yeah
so again amazon is again it's
such a big uh company
that uh their products can be divided
into programs yes their product can be
revealed into programs so the program in
itself would be so big that they would
be requiring one or multiple managers to
handle that so
there may have come this term called
program manager
uh
so another another question i think you
have raised that point
is the important the skills required
as a product manager you have raised few
few points in middle about the skills
required so if you can elaborate on that
and another question that i want to add
to that is that
the problem solving skill because i feel
that as a product manager a very
important thing is problem solving
because you may come across a lot of
issues as a product manager so
uh so it's a three part question uh i'll
break it down first is the skills
required as a product manager then the
importance of problem solving and the
third part is as an mba student people
who are in the mba how important it is
to participate in case study
competitions and develop that problem
solving ability
okay
uh what was your first question the
first question was the skills required
for a product
skills required okay so i'll i'll i'll
explain this again
by giving an example of myself like my
day-to-day activity when i reach office
what i what i do that will give you an
uh you know hint or a some knowledge
about what are the basically channels on
which the upload manager works okay
so first you reach reach the office
first i reach the office then i have a
morning meeting or a scrum call kind of
thing wherein we uh as a team we discuss
what are the things that we need to
follow up and what are the things we
need to do first thing is crumb meeting
so scrum meeting
there is a tool for that but again we
don't do we just go to the whiteboard
and discuss so the first thing is
planning okay you need to have proper
planning because you need to be
in control of your entire project you
need to know what is happening in each
and every as i said it's a
multi-stakeholder thing
you would not be doing everything you
need to follow from different
stakeholders but if anything goes wrong
in that product you are going to be
answerable for that anything any issue
comes even if it
you know
gains uh
appreciation you are going to be the
part of that appreciation okay so it's
basically a double legit soul
okay
the first thing is planning you need to
be in control of your project of
everything
number two
we then what i do is i go and so we are
currently doing a research project on
our app
wherein we have we have our own research
department for icse bank so but we have
also hired some
external vendors they are they are going
to do our research what when i talk
about market research
that's again a pointer market this has
quantitative studies and qualitative
studies many of most of you uh mba
people will be knowing this
so that's the exercise that the agencies
take and they would give us inputs
those inputs
you as a product manager will get those
inputs okay
now
once you get those inputs how are you
going to implement that in your
area or your product
that is what is your
okay
this is point one i'll again come back
to this when i talk about uh problem
solving skills okay this is one input
number two
uh
then i go to our design we have a design
uh mock-up call where wherein our
designers again our designers are maybe
in some companies they have in-house
designs in some companies they have
external partners for designs
so we have a design
call with our designers
we discuss about
so if they would be having some designs
to show
wireframes to show us or some low
fidelity designs low fidelity designs
means
not everything would be there not all
the colors would be there it's just the
way how that is that the journey is
going to look okay it may be for black
and white in color okay so we'll have
we're going to discuss that
and as a product manager you need to
evaluate that okay no this journey is
not good this is this is how confusing
for the customer this this has to be
better done you have to give flaw
problem statement to the designers and
ask them to come up with solutions
ask them for multiple solutions so that
because what happens you may have to
show other journeys to your higher
stakeholders you may have to get them
approved so you need to ask for multiple
options so that
you can give more options to your
stakeholders to approve that
that's one thing
so yeah so you need to have you can say
uh
some good logical skills
so that you can understand what is right
for the customer and what is wrong for
the customer what is easy for the
customer what is difficult for the
customer yeah so for that you need to uh
have a lot of data with you about the
customer
right
so
data retrieval is one thing from either
from secondary sources or from your
primary reports of your department you
need to keep that with you handy some
important figures figures how many
logins happen today how many activations
happen today what is the total number of
transactions in the app today you need
to have those figures handy so that it
will it will unconsciously give you some
insights
okay
if every day you would be keeping track
you will come
here why is today today's homing what
happened let's let me check let me ask
the
live issue team what happened today okay
are there many live issues
yesterday release went to in the uh ios
store once was it was there some kind of
issue for which
the number of activations have come down
these kind of questions they need to
come up in your mind because this is not
going to come in anyone else's mind this
is not going to come up in the
developer's mind not going to come to
the tester's mind not going to come up
in a designer's mind because they are
doing their job right they are doing
their job properly what they
yes exactly so you these kind of issues
should come because you are going to be
asked why from your in your reports in
your meetings in your meetings why this
came down
why have this come come down you need to
be ready with those answers and okay and
you need to know as well okay so that's
number two then uh
maybe after lunch
we have a meeting with a text team okay
when
we groom them with our requirements
or if there is something that they have
we have already groomed but they have
come with their questions their doubts
we resolve them
yeah
and then they at times still yeah this
is very difficult to do the kind of
journey that you have made it's very
difficult so we tell them no no
tell us why it can't be done or it can
something so it's basically you know a
discussion goes on at times it becomes
intense but it's okay it's for the good
only
so this is what so then
here what you need is number one is you
should
what i said you need to have some kind
of tech understanding so that you can
tackle the dev at time c what happens is
we work in a very chaotic environment
there are so many uh releases going on
there are live issues that
we know that this has to go uh in this
uh google build in this play store build
in this ios build so if the developers
are under pressure the you know the
the managers are under pressure so what
happens is at times the developers try
to tell that actually this can be done
because
what is the problem show me the code you
may not understand but you try to get a
sense of what why that code was written
okay and you need to tackle that because
at the end it's your purpose you are
you know deliverable to create a great
journey okay
so you can't really bog down
by these kind of you know statements
yeah at times it is very genuine that
yeah
then yes you will come up to plan b
okay
so these kind of skills for that
negotiation some kind of negotiation
skills not exactly negotiation of skills
but yeah some kind of negotiation skills
some kind of convincing skills
these kind of skills are required
yeah
uh
what else what else yeah
at the end of the day
what i do is whatever has been done i
try to pull it together because again
that's my job to collate everything
together then i kind of
um forecast how the product is growing
is it going growing as per plan
or are we lagging somewhere behind if
yes
it may have a significant improvement on
the product
these kind of things you need to think
so mostly it's more you know thinking
you need to think think about your
product this is number one so i think
that answers the first uh question right
the skill sets require yeah
number two is the problem solving skills
right yeah problem solving and uh
relating that to case studies and case
study competition that will help in
development
[Music]
okay
see obviously
problem solving is required skill is
required
but what
uh
precedes the problem solving skills you
know is the
right problem statement
yeah if you don't and that is
more uh
i as permits is tougher than having a
solution to the problem
we are exposed to so much information
now we have all the solutions in our
book okay
but the problem is
that solution is not fitting to the
problem statement because the problem
statement has not been defined properly
yeah so the first and foremost thing of
a thing that a product manager should do
is first ask the right questions
yeah or
put down the right problem statement
that is the first and foremost thing
if that is done and then
if you are able to find a good solution
to it then well and good if not there
are so many stakeholders you are working
with
each one of them can come up with a
solution
okay so if you ask me and again it's my
personal opinion problem solving skill
is required
but more important
is to
put down the right problem statement and
it's not a easy thing to do it's not
easy
uh this app is being used by more than
uh
two cores of customers okay
we i cannot segment all these customers
right
obviously there are
different type of people different type
of preferences so
nobody can tell you for sure what is
right for this app so what you have to
do is you know you have to find out you
prioritize things so prioritizing
you have to put the right the bank on
problem statement
then solution
yeah
another another important thing is that
sometimes we feel
everything the best i put but somehow
the customer is not liking it so it
ultimately requires why that happens you
know why that happens you know because
we do not
know the entire experience that the
customer goes through or we do not try
to find out
we have to find out that first
okay and uh so what happened so these
kind of issues i face almost every day i
have
problem statements i have problems to
solve okay
what first thing is i need to put the
problem statement properly in a very
descriptive way so that people
understand this is the problem we have
number two is
there are so many stakeholders i call
them up for a meeting i discuss the
problems i give my view i think this is
how it should be done i think this is
how it should be done then
i
leave the
discussion open
so there are so many people they will
come up with their solutions okay you
need to know them now
okay
your your job as a product manager is
also to collate the information that you
get from others the solutions that you
get from others then after that after
note that down you have to go through
the solutions because you are the only
person who knows every
domain of the product they don't they
might have
the example that you give it's
applicable for them also they might be
thinking
but you know your technical possible
names
so you have the idea that solution a not
that visible solution b okay looks good
can be done can be taken up for
discussion you have to chalk that out so
now you have a problem statement and a
couple of potential
solutions
yeah
so that's how and then again you go up
for your season management you discuss
that and then uh your senior management
will tell that okay go ahead with this
or do whatever you want it's okay that
depends from companies to company here
our senior management they give us the
freedom to okay you think this is the
right foot to put please do no problem
we are there for you so
this is how it happens
so so that so coming down to the
question yeah this is how you
and mo 99 percent of time you will not
be having a single one-stop solution for
a problem okay because problems are very
complex let me tell you that
you would be having okay at times you
will have phase weight solution
so that's what it is you have to plan
properly the solutions
yeah uh another question that i would
like to ask since we have been
discussing product management and all
its intricacies for a very long time uh
another question that i want to ask is
regarding your mba
uh so a lot of our audience would be
entering into their mba right now
uh like entering into the program the
interviews are going on some people have
got selected into colleges so any any
advice you have for them in order to
make these two years of mba uh more
fruitful in order to get more out of it
and even as in terms of a product
manager point of view
in future they see themselves as a
product manager so if you have any tips
regarding that also
okay so see there are
if i again let me segment uh the mba
aspirants into two parts okay
one is
they are they know what they are going
to do they know why they're having doing
this mba
um maybe they uh
they have done something in your pre-mba
job experience and they know that if i
do an mba that's going to kind of
expand okay
that my domain will increase in this
area and that's going to help me
there are some executive mbas also fall
in those categories as well okay so for
those kind of people i don't think they
need any guidance person they just for
example
okay let's say if if someone who has
already been a product manager before
mba there are some people who are poor
friends before an mbbs they have all
this idea about what to do what not to
do so they don't need much of guidance
to sail through the mba okay
but okay let's let's you know ignore
those segments of people because they
are very few actually okay
most of the people who do an mba that's
including me at that time
we didn't know what to do
like for me
uh i was i did not like so before mb i
was working with infosys
i did not like the work i did i like i
did not enjoy the coding that i did
it was a good project everybody was good
to be in great workplace but i did not
enjoy the work i was doing it did not
satisfy me so i thought let me go for a
mba
i went with a zero
i mean open mind i don't i didn't know
what to do i didn't know what uh field
i'm joining
so
i went with open mind only and even
during my placements till my i got
placed i didn't know that i will be
going forward manager or something so
what i did was very basic i
uh
did a great
networking did get
networking and then i uh
i was okay in all these subjects
i had interest in some i i liked
marketing subjects i like some
uh you know research subjects
so
yes we also had i.t related subjects
okay i was okay in that i mean okay i
knew i was from the iit industry so i
knew most of most of the things
so
so basically you know you need to what i
would suggest is in these two years you
need to
set up a mindset
yeah a mindset to
create something
out of thin air
when it comes to digital products
okay
um or to you know solve a problem as you
say solution oriented
okay your solution may not be the best
solution but if you are at least giving
a solution in the room then
you're better off than
most of the people
solution oriented
i mean there are people who are always
focusing on the problems
opposite
be the solution given
is
someone from the senior management of a
very big company uh told that in one of
his books i if you are an employee come
with me with solutions and not problems
because
that's how you will
be differentiated because
out of 199 people come with problems but
one comes with solution that is how you
rise up the ladder
of course of course of course so as a
product manager at times you have to
create the problem also you have to
understand the problem which nobody in
the
entire uh you know your entire group or
a larger group would be knowing you need
to understand the problems and then find
the solution for them also so when you
go to the senior management you can go
and tell your problem
this is the problem and this is how we
are planning to tackle it then only they
will listen to you then or else they
would they will say why have come to us
with the problem why are you there right
so yeah so that kind of mindset it's a
mindset it will not happen overnight
yeah but two years in the b school life
it's
it's quite possible that to develop that
mindset assuming that i'm starting from
zero if you already have that mindset
being great you can just build up on
that
so i would what i would say is in this
two years
develop great networks
talk to people discuss about case
studies yeah
discuss about what is happening in the
world yeah i'm not only talking about
corporate things or
you know
about uh technical things
discuss in general
yeah what is happening in geopolitics
what is happening in uh
our
technology what is happening in stocks
what is happening in uh financial
markets
discuss all these things because all
these are going to shape up your mind to
develop that kind of attitude you know
problem solving attitude
plus i think what mba teaches you is
conflict management yeah chaos
management that is very important to
having you because
believe me after once you go out and
step into the industry corporate is full
of conflicts and here's go to the best
of the companies go to the
worst of the companies one thing is
common is chaos everywhere it's cures
yeah so you need to have that
not to lose your cool not to lose your
mind when it comes to chaotic situations
you're going to face that very regularly
yeah
that is called and at times you need to
uh
you know stakeholder management we say
so you need to manage all people around
you all the stakeholders all the team
members
these are some of the you know it's not
like you can read from a book and do you
need to interact with people
and you need to talk to people listen to
people right
and that is a
nba
again when i talk about mba i mean the
campus
okay not from home what that happened i
think a few batches in the past
it's a very very unfortunate thing
uh because as per me mba should be
school is best enjoyed when you stay in
the campus 24 into seven
yeah
and because you the kind of
camaraderie you make in these two years
it's going to take you a long way yeah
and that and this is the breeding ground
where you can develop this mindset yeah
because you know you're never going to
get these kind of discussions later
yeah
it's a very important point that you
rate that whenever you go into an mba
for the nba students all with the
mindset that i will uh maybe you may
having a problem solving mindset mindset
of coming with solutions but in nba
you'll get a lot of chances also because
you'll get a lot of problems also
exactly but have problems in terms of
your studies in terms of discussions in
the classes
and even in terms of your work that you
would be doing so having that developing
that mindset uh will help you in the
conference as well
yeah
uh answer as you come to the end of the
means near the end of the podcast i
would also like to give you some advice
for people who have done their mba done
their two years and are moving into the
culprit so if you have any advice for
them any advice that you followed were
given to you by your mentors and you
have used it in the corporate and you
have okay this is something that i have
benefited from using this advice so if
you want to give some advice to them
oh see again when you're going to
cooperate you're going to different
roles
so different roles will demand different
skills from you okay so i will not go
into this that that will aspect what i
can say is that is something
i have learned from icse bank
is it
be approachable and be available to your
team members
try to be available to your team members
as
much as you can because most after md
era most
[Music]
yeah so you need to be perspective
perceptive to people around you
be approachable be available to them
try to
you know
give them directions as i said
problem statement solution directions
requirement
try to give mv be very clear in your
coming communication that's very
important because
blunders have been
lenders have offered because of
miscommunication
okay so and that depends on your role as
well where you are if you are in a
customer-centric role your communication
needs to be impeccable
or else things may turn you know
so that's number one communication
number two is approachable
uh number three is
we be passionate about the role that
you're doing all of this it doesn't
matter see initially
feels very exciting you feel very
energetic
but over the time you understand how
things work and then you become very
passive
okay so then if you are not passionate
about the work that you are doing
then your energy levels decrease your
interest declines and i think that's why
people switch
right
they want to
again money is a factor but
this is also
in the back end of their mind they think
about this as well it somewhat becomes
robotic like okay i have to come and do
this do this do this it becomes like a
machine kind of thing at times at times
it is
understood as well see if you are doing
the same thing for the next five years
you have you have extracted everything
that you could have from that role and
then it's fine you can move on to the
next thing that's not a problem
but uh yeah but you need to be
passionate about it and before you take
a decision to you know change your role
or something
know everything in that world because
you never know future
aspect
right you never know that so it's better
you understand and
each and every integrity of the rule
that you are currently in
before you go to the next chapter you
should go to the next chapter i'm not
saying you don't you have to go you have
to grow right when you're growing if
you're not getting the space to grow you
have to change the space right it's very
logical
but yeah before you change it
take absorb the most out of that yeah
so thank you sir we i think i have never
listened to someone with such detailed
description of product manager i think
people would have no doubt after that
what a product manager does what are the
right skills required because you in
such great depth you have explained what
exactly the work of product manager you
have given an example of your own
day-to-day work means from eight o'clock
to till at night you've given everything
in in very great detail so yeah and also
a very important point that you raised a
growth mindset as well as an mba student
that problem-solving mindset so i think
our audience will uh take that absorb
that from you and yeah benefit that in
their careers
so
thank you thank you
thank you so much thank you for all the
good things you said about me
i wish you all the best i wish your uh
viewers all the best and
just the thing is don't take too much
pressure
just
analyze it from as i said in word
manager everything you need to look from
you know higher perspective then things
become very clear to you and once that
clarity pitches in in your mind you will
be able to find your way in yeah and
that's for life as well as for
cooperative
yeah
okay thank you that's a great piece of
advice to end the culture
thank you thank you thank you it's my
pleasure thank you bye-bye have a great
day
[Music]
you